Gunjan Singh

House No. 331, Sadiq Nagar, Sector- 3, South Delhi, New Delhi 8920586102

https://www.linkedin.com/in/gunjan-s-25b532112

• singhgunjan904@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Committed academic lecturer with two years of experience in teaching undergraduate courses in psychology. Actively participate in continued learning through various conferences and professional research. Industrious and innovative individual with a proven history of strong student rapport.

Work experience

Visiting Faculty, 03/2019 to Present Amity University, Noida

• Subjects teaching- Social Psychology, Research methods, Psycho-oncology and Positive- Psychotherapy.

Pro-term Lecturer/Assistant Professor, 07/2017 to 07/2019 **Graphic Era (Deemed to be University)** – Dehradun, Uttrakhand

- Instructed students using lectures, discussions and demonstrations in several psychology subjects.
- Applied innovative teaching methods to encourage student learning objectives.
- Reviewed program materials and coordinated updates to keep department materials relevant and accurate.
- Evaluated and supervised student activities and performance levels to provide reports on academic progress.
- Provided academic advisement to students including assistance with thesis and dissertation development.

Counselling Psychologist, 07/2017 to 07/2019 **Graphic Era (Deemed to be University)** – Dehradun, Uttrakhand

- Created, implemented and evaluated developmental outreach programs, presentations, workshops and other activities to facilitate students/staff growth.
- Documented client progress in confidential files.
- Consulted with patients on issues pertaining to relationship issues, substance abuse, career and other problems.
- Interviewed, observed, and surveyed patients in order to gain necessary information for psychological diagnosis.
- Performed research on effectiveness of interventions and proposed changes to intervention structures based on evaluation outcomes.

Invited Guest Lecturer,

Police Training Centre, Narendernagar, Uttrakhand

- Implemented and evaluated outreach presentation based lectures to facilitate the Junior Prosecution Officers
- Documented their progress in confidential files.

Education

Education

Master of Art: Applied Psychology, 2017 University of Delhi – South Campus, New Delhi,

First Division with 68% Marks

B.Sc. Honours: Clinical Psychology, 2015 **Amity University** - Gurugram, Haryana Distinction with 8.95 CGPA

Certification: Behavioural Science, French and Communication skills 2015

Amity University - Gurugram, Haryana.

Diploma: Neuro-Linguistic Programming (Level – 1 for Practitioner)

Training/Internship

Indraprastha Apollo Hospitals, New Delhi, March 2017 - April 2017

Psychology Intern

- Under the tutelage of Dr. Rakhi Anand (Senior Consultant), assisted her for different assessments and diagnosis.
- Designed intervention and treatment plan for better prognosis.
- Assisted the head psychologist in therapies like CBT, BT, counselling (family, group, individual, marriage counselling) along with relaxation technique like JPMR.

All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, August 2016 - September 2016

Short term Trainee (Neuropsychology Department)

- Memory Assessment and Screening for Cognitive Decline.
- Cognitive Rehabilitation for Dementia/ Alzheimer's Dementia and cognitive re-training for decline in Memory/Executive Functioning.
- Family guidance and monitoring of progress.

National Institute of Public Cooperation and Child Development, MWCD, New Delhi, June 2016 - July 2016 Psychology Intern

- Worked under the supervision of Smt. Vandana Thapar, (Deputy Director, PSD) to assist for report writing, assessment and diagnosis relate to adolescents issues on delinquency, Intellectual disability, Learning disabity, Austism Spectrum Disorder.etc
- Worked under the supervision of Dr, Vandana Sharma, (Research Wing) for slogan writing and research on "**Beti Bachao Beti Padhao'** Abhiyan, Menstrual Health and Child Nutrition to spread awareness in the countryside villages of Delhi. Contributed to gather research data to develop NIPCCD's annual research report focusing women health for the year 2016.

MINDLER, Taxmann, New Delhi, October 2015 – February 2016

Psychometric Design Intern

- Worked in the construction of India's first ever psychological battery to assess the Personality, Aptitude, Emotional intelligence and Interest of school children to assess right career, developed under a team of psychometricians and psychologist.
- Was responsible for scale construction, establishing reliability, validity of scale and Research.

Ministry of Human Resource and Development, New Delhi, January 2015 - March 2015

Psychology Intern

- worked for a project e-PG-Pathshala, funded by MHRD.
- Designed quality e-material for psychology students to support the post graduate level study.

Gwalior Mansik Arogyashala, Govt. of Madhya Pradesh, Gwalior, May 2014 - July 2014

Clinical Psychology Intern

- · Was responsible for assessment, and diagnosis of both psychotic and neurotic patients
- Attended regular OPD, visits to indoor, outdoor and general ward patients.
- Therapy observations.

Manav Vikas Vishesh Vidyalaya, Pataudhi, Gurugram, September 2013 - March 2014 Intern

- Regular clinical visit to the school
- •Imparted training on assessment and diagnosis of children with special needs.

Conferences Attended

- International Conference on Neurosciences and Buddhist Psychology, September 2017
- National Conference on Knowledge and innovation for Sustainable Growth April 29, 2018 Impact of Emotional Intelligence on Self –Esteem
- International Conference Contemporary Issues in Business Innovation Technology & Social Studies, On June 1-2, 2018
- International Conference On Military Psychology & Counselling Aug 14, 2018, Warmcamp 2018
- International Conference On Cognitive Behavioural Interventions- ICCBI Sept 27-29, 2018
- International Conference on Military Stress and Resilience, Belgrade, Serbia, Novemer, 2018
- First PAN IIT International Management Conference Nov 30- Dec 2, 2018
- National Conference on, Indian Economy: Policy Intervention for Sustainable Growth, IEPISG, March 11-12, 2019
- ICSSR-IMPRESS Sponsored International Conference on Employment skills and rural transformation, April 11-12,2019

Conference Presentations/Proceedings/ Journal Papers/ Book Chapters

- Agrawal, D., & Singh, G. (2018). International Conference on Cognitive Behavioural Intervention- ICCBI 2018. In *Impact of Cognitive Behavioural Therapy on Bipolar Disorder*.
- Bhatt, J., & Singh, G. (2018). International Conference on Cognitive Behavioural Intervention- ICCBI 2018. In *Impact of Cognitive Behavioural Therapy on Obsessive Compulsive Disorder*.
- Dimri, S., & Singh, G. (OAD). Impact of Cognitive Behavioural Therapy on Voyeuristic Disorder (Voyeurism). *International Journal of Social Sciences Review, Special Issue, "Transdisciplinary CBT"*, 7, 42–46.
- Goel, S., & Singh, G. (2018). Emotional Intelligence, Resilience, Job Satisfaction and Employees performance in Organizations. In *Management Research and Innovation* (1st ed., pp. 164–171). Bharti publication.
- Lal, A. R., & Singh, G. (2018). First PAN-IIT International Management Conference- 2018. In *Psychological Factors Determine Investors Decision making towards Financial Avenues: A study in Dehradun*.
- Mittal, S., & Singh, G. (2018). The Role of Risk Taking Behaviour in Increasing Juvenile Delinquency: An Indian Perspective. In *Impact of Cognitive Behavioural Therapy on Social Anxiety Disorder*.
- Rawat, S., Deshpande, A. P., & Singh, G. (2018). Self-Perception as Stress Buffering in Military. In *Stress in Military Profession* (1st ed., pp. 65–80). Strategic Research Institute, University of Defence, Republic of Serbia.
- Sharma, D., & Singh, G. Impact of Cognitive Behavioural Therapy on Schizophrenia. *International Journal of Social Sciences Review, Special Issue, "Transdisciplinary CBT"*, 7, 16–20.
- Singh, G., Rawat, S., & Deshpande, A. P. (2018). Study of Locus of Control and Self- Esteem among military cadets. In *Stress in Military Profession* (1st ed., pp. 81–112). Belgrade, Belgrade: Strategic Research Institute, University of Defence, Republic of Serbia.
- Singh, G., &. (2018). Resilience among Cadets: A comparative study with college students in India. In *Cadet Diary, Psychology if Warrior Ethos and Cadet Leadership Development* (1st ed., pp. 77–92). Rawat Publications, New Delhi.
- Singh, R., & Singh, G. (2018). First PAN-IIT Management Conference- 2018. In Psychological Impact of Advertisement.
- Singh, R., & Singh, G. (2019). '#' Hashtags: A Staple in Social Media Marketing. In *Emerging Trends in Management Practices* 2019(1st ed., pp. 158–163). New Delhi, New Delhi.

Thappa, A., & Singh, G. (2018). First PAN-IIT International Management Conference. In *Resilience, Personal Growth Initiative* and Employees Productivity at Workplace.

Participation

- Workshop on, "Differentiating Combat Stress, Post-Traumatic Stress and Traumatic Disability Stress" Belgrade, 6-7 November, 2018
- Organised a workshop on, "Mental **Health Issues and its Prevention**" on the occasion of world mental Health Day, 10 October, 2018.
- Workshop on, "Crafting and Conducting High Quality Research" Graphic Era University, 28-29 April, 2018
- Coca-Cola YouthSpeak Forum, AIESEC, Graphic Era University, Dehradun, 21 March, 2018
- Organic Brain Syndromes with Focus on Alzheimer's Dementia, Case studies and Clinical Appraisal Session, Moolchand Medcity,24 June,2017.
- Workshop on, "Thematic Apperception Test" Department of Applied Psychology, University of Delhi, South Campus, 17 January, 2017
- **Talking Across Generation, UNESCO**, Mahatama Gandhi Institute of Education for Peace and Sustainable Development, Indian Habitat Centre, 15 Febuaray, 2016
- Workshop on, "**Leadership and Team Building**" Rajiv Gandhi National Institute of Youth Development, 22 January, 2016.
- International Conference and Digitisation Exhibition, Constitution Club of India, New-Delhi, 8-9 January, 2016
- Workshop on, "Clinical and Experimental Hypnosis" Jawaharlal Nehru University, 25-27 October, 2013
- Workshop on, "Learning Disability" Indian Institute of Psychology, 24-28 June 2013
- AMI'FEST,2013, An Inter University Fest, 14- 15 February, 2013

Professional Development

- Organised and Conducted a workshop at WARMCAMP International Military Psychology Conference in Pune,
 2018 with eminent military psychologists from abroad as keynote speakers
- First and only ever Indian to be invited by Serbian Armed Forces as a keynote speaker for 'the Military Psychology Sciences Conference, Nov 2018, Hosted by Ministry of Defence, Serbia to celebrate 75 years of Military Psychology.
- International Book Published Abroad in 2018 Authored a chapter 'Study of Locus of Control and Self Esteem among Cadets' in 'International Thematic Collection .Stress in the Military Profession Achievements and Perspectives' (Serbian Armed Forces Academy.
- International Book Published Abroad in 2018 Co-authored a chapter 'Self Perception in the Armed Forces' in 'International Thematic Collection .Stress in the Military Profession Achievements and Perspectives' (Serbian Armed Forces Academy.
- International Book Published Abroad in 2018 Co-authored a chapter 'Communicative Behaviour as Transformational Power of Military Leadership.' in 'From "Knowing" to "Doing": International Perspectives on Leading Effectively' (Canada Defence Academy Press In Press).
- International Book Published Abroad in 2018 Co-authored a chapter 'Self Awareness and Attitude Training for High Performance in the Military 'in 'International Perspectives on Military Performance '(Canada Defence Academy In Press).
- International Book Published Abroad in 2018 Authored a chapter 'Cognitive and Volitional Perspectives in Enhancing Human Factors in Military Performance 'in 'International Perspectives on Military Performance' (Canada Defence Academy. In Press).
- Book Published in 2018 'Cadet Diary Warrior Ethos and leadership development for Cadets' with contributions from foreign authors across many countries .(Rawat Publications ,Jaipur ,India –ISBN NO 978-81-316-0-985-9)
- Successfully Completed two weeks Faculty Development Programme on "Entrepreneurship" sponsored by NSTEDB, Dept. of Science and Technology, New Delhi, 12- 23 April,2018.

- Successfully Conducted a workshop, A neuropsychological
- Awarded as Innovative Academia for fostering an ecosystem bridging government, India Innovation Challenge Design Contest 2018, DST and TEXAS INSTRUMENTS
- Successfully Finished the Half –Marathon,(21 KM), Amity University, 28 September, 2014

Skills

- Resilient
- Adaptive
- Adroit
- Organisation skills.
- Strong communication and interpersonal skills.

Personal Details

Date of Birth – 21 December, 1993.

Place- New Delhi.